AMOS HAN

+1.201.421.6904 | amos.han.mcrp@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/amos-han-mcrp

SUMMARY

Hold a Master of Public Informatics and Master of City and Regional Planning degrees and concentration in public transportation from the Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy at Rutgers University. Skills in stastistics, programming, data management, data analytics, visualization, spatial analysis, surveying, research and application. Interests in micromobility, public transportation, bike/ped, big data, data analytics and the integration of transportation with public informatics to provide a deeper understanding of and critical analysis in the fields of city planning, policy and management.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL: Adobe Creative Suite (Acrobat Pro, InDesign, Photoshop), Analysis, AutoCAD, ArcMap, ArcGIS Pro, Data Analytics, Jupyter Notebook, Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint), Mac, RStudio, Sketchup, Stata Stastical Software, Strategy, Technical writing, Urban Photography, Windows

LANGUAGES: English, Korean

EDUCATION

MASTER OF PUBLIC INFORMATICS (Concentration: Urban Informatics)

5/2021

Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ Relevant coursework: Graphical Communications/Design, Applied Multivariate Methods, Global Data Analytics

CERTIFICATE IN TRANSPORTATION STUDIES

1/2021

Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ

MASTER OF CITY AND REGIONAL PLANNING (Concentration: Transportation Policy and Planning)

5/2017

Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ Relevant coursework: Public Transit Planning and Management; Urban Transportation Planning; Transportation and Land Use

BACHELOR OF ARTS – ENGINEERING STUDIES (Concentration: Construction Management)

5/2014

Lafayette College, Easton, PA

EXPERIENCE

Alan M. Voorhees Transportation Center, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ (remote) 3/2021-5/2021 STUDENT RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Explored key concepts, desktop analysis and looked towards to future for New Jersey communities to explore options for a "fifteen-minute city," a community where amenities are available within fifteen minutes of walking
- Conducted environmental justice and equity analyses as part of transportation planning.
- Researched case study on Singapore's "twenty-minute town" and "45-minute city" implementation to present an example of a leading practice in the "fifteen-minute city" concept.

Mongolia International University, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

2/2018-12/2018

VISITING PROFESSOR – Engineering Mathematics and Precalculus

- Taught Engineering Mathematics and Precalculus in a university setting.
- Conducted research on urban planning issues.
- Proposed a monorail and a bus rapid transit line by identifying ideal routes expected ridership and current traffic volume.
- Researched traffic congestion and inefficient bus system in Ulaanbaatar, such as overcrowding of buses, cause of overpopulation and common points of interests.
- Identified other potential solutions, such as converting Ulaanbaatar into a multi-centric city.

Alan M. Voorhees Transportation Center, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ **4**, **LIGHT RAIL SURVEYOR (3/2017-5/2017)**

4/2016-5/2017

- Conducted field work as a survey agent on board the Hudson-Bergen Light Rail (HBLR) in Hudson County, NJ, and on HBLR platforms, reporting to the Executive Director at the beginning and end of each day.
- Distributed ridership and demographic surveys to passengers, assessing the number of English and Spanish surveys distributed, and the number of school-aged children on board utilizing the transit system.

ON-BOARD BUS SURVEYOR (4/2016-5/2016, 9/2016-11/2016)

- Completed field work as a survey agent on New Jersey Transit buses within Hudson County, NJ. Reported to the Assistant Director of Research at the beginning and end of each day.
- Distributed ridership and demographic surveys to passengers, recording data to include the number of passenger boardings and alightings at specific stops.

Ward and Associates, San Francisco, CA (remote, contract position) GIS CONSULTANT

7/2016-8/2016

• Developed demographics, including race, ethnicity and poverty levels, and municipal maps utilizing ArcGIS for the California High-Speed Rail corridor between San Francisco and San Jose with a half-mile buffer in the study area.

Center for Advanced Infrastructure and Transportation, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, Piscataway, NJ 6/2016-7/2016 ON-BOARD FIELD RESEARCHER

• Observed, collected and analyzed data in several NJ locations to gain knowledge of the skills/abilities of adults presenting autism and the need for paratransit services. Assessed data to provide recommendations for enhanced services and encourage independent travel.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS/STUDIOS

Micromobility Safety, Equity, and Climate Change Studio, New Brunswick, NJ (remote)

Spring 2021

GRADUATE PLANNING STUDIO MEMBER – Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy

- Collaborate with a team of 11 students to expand implementation of the Rutgers e-scooter program into New Brunswick and Highland Park.
- Expertly assess current conditions in the area of study to determine the safety level of the bike/ped infrastructure
- Suggest ways to enable population without a smartphone, internet access and/or bank account to access e-scooters and receive information.

Irvington Bike/Ped Studio, New Brunswick, NJ

Fall 2016

GRADUATE PLANNING STUDIO MEMBER – Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy

- Collaborated with a team of 15 students to propose rehabilitation of the bicycle/pedestrian infrastructure in Irvington, NJ.
- Expertly assessed current conditions along sidewalks and roads in the area of study to determine safety with scoring based on sidewalk and crosswalk conditions, cleanliness, driver behavior and general safety/appearance.
- Utilized ArcGIS to develop a bicycle suitability map, and proofread a studio report draft, making comments/critiques.

Urban Transit Studio, New Brunswick, NJ

Spring 2016

GRADUATE PLANNING STUDIO MEMBER - Edward J. Bloustein School of Planning and Public Policy

- Collaborated with a team of 15 students to propose new bus lines in Union County, NJ for New Jersey Transit to improve service and satisfy gaps between two rail lines, and expedite commutes within the county and to regional core hubs.
- Estimated timetables for proposed routes, and determined land use/demographics, including population density, race and poverty levels in addition to reviewing concerns/recommendations with stakeholders such as business owners, municipal council members, planners and police officers during meetings.

COMMUNITY SERVICE

AFFORDABLE HOUSING ADVOCATE AND CYCLIST VOLUNTEER, Bike and Build (2017)

June-September 2017

- Raised \$4,800 for affordable housing and cycled 4,000 miles from Portsmouth, NH to Bellingham, WA while volunteering and advocating for affordable housing en route.
- Presented on Bike & Build and affordable housing to local communities.
- Reviewed and scored Bike & Build grant applications submitted by affordable housing organizations to select qualified applicants.